<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Fuel Security on Save Marsden Point</title>
    <link>/tags/fuel-security/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Fuel Security on Save Marsden Point</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 02 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/fuel-security/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Cabinet From Hell Rejects Saving Refinery</title>
      <link>/event/2021-11-02-cabinet-closes-the-refinery/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/event/2021-11-02-cabinet-closes-the-refinery/</guid>
      <description>After a period of consultation Megan Woods signed the deth notice of the refinery with the release of the cabinet paper MBIE Cabinet Paper - Fuel supply resilience without a domestic oil refinery.
Subject to a final decision by Refining NZ, due by 30 September 2021, oil refining operations are expected to cease between March and June 2022, after which 100 per cent of refined fuels will be imported. I propose to progress development of options to ensure domestic fuel stock levels remain adequate, as a means of supporting fuel supply resilience, as New Zealand transitions away from fossil fuels.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fuel Security in NZ</title>
      <link>/topics/nz-fuel-security/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/topics/nz-fuel-security/</guid>
      <description>Despite government claims to the contrary, closure of Marsden Point has clearly decreased New Zealand&amp;rsquo;s fuel security because we have simply removed an option for supply, Where we previously may have imported direclty, imported crude or with modification process our own crude, now we are restricted to import only. The downside risks of no fuel scenarios would seems to have significantly increased. The government has probably overly foucsed on the benign recent geopolitical environemnt and given too much emphasis to the climate change policies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NZ Labour government and NZ Refining Complicitiy</title>
      <link>/topics/why/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/topics/why/</guid>
      <description>Letter By Dave
Introduction This document intends to outline the New Zealand Labour governments’ complicity in the decommissioning of the refinery owned and operated by Refining NZ (RNZ) located at Marsden Point from being a crude oil refinery into a finished fuel product import only terminal. Additionally it will highlight various events, actions or responses that have occurred over the timeline of early 2020 up until events of the last few days.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
