<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Timeline on Save Marsden Point</title>
    <link>/tags/timeline/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Timeline on Save Marsden Point</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 16 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/timeline/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>MBIE Report - REFINING NZ IMPACT OF CONVERSION TO FUELS TERMINAL</title>
      <link>/reports/mbie-hale-twomey-fuel-security-costs-benefits/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/reports/mbie-hale-twomey-fuel-security-costs-benefits/</guid>
      <description>2020-12-16 Fuel security and fuel stockholding costs and benefits  It is currently reviewing its refining business in the context of challenging global refining market conditions, and is considering options that include reducing its refining capacity and closing the refinery.
 Executive Summary The Ministry of Business, Innovation and Employment (MBIE) is the Government’s lead adviser on national fuel security and periodically reviews fuel security policy settings. This review updates the previous reviews concentrating on national fuel supply risks and fuel security policies, particularly domestic fuel stockholding policies, under plausible market scenarios including closure of the Marsden Point oil refinery.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MBIE Report - REFINING NZ IMPACT OF CONVERSION TO FUELS TERMINAL</title>
      <link>/reports/mbie-hale-twomey-impact-import-only/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/reports/mbie-hale-twomey-impact-import-only/</guid>
      <description>2020-03-23 Refining NZ: Impact of conversion to fuels terminal commisioned by MBIE - and subsequently ignored, made the following points about the impact of a move to an import only model:
 A reduction in physical inventories (expected to be 25-30%) that ultimately is likely to impact New Zealand&amp;rsquo;s supply security An increased cost of compliance to meet the IEA membership requirement to hold stocks covering at least 90 days of New Zealand&amp;rsquo;s daily net import requirement; The loss of the coastal tanker operation and the expertise associated with that (albeit import tankers would increase so there would still be plenty of ships on the coast) No ability in New Zealand to correct product that is significantly off-specification which needs to be taken into account with stock level decisions Possible issues with jet import availability if it all needs to meet a lower sulphur specification for transport via RAP; No local supply of sulphur for fertiliser; replacement supply needed for CO2; Loss of technical processing expertise; Loss of ability to process New Zealand crude in a major supply emergency (global meltdown or pandemic where New Zealand might be isolated for a time).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MBIE Megan Woods Cabinet Paper - Fuel supply resilience without a domestic oil refinery - Decision to Close</title>
      <link>/reports/mbie-cabpaper-woods-closes-the-refinery/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/reports/mbie-cabpaper-woods-closes-the-refinery/</guid>
      <description>MBIE Oil security in New Zealand I propose to progress development of options to ensure domestic fuel stock levels remain adequate, as a means of supporting fuel supply resilience, as New Zealand transitions away from fossil fuels.
implications for meeting the Government’s first emissions reduction budget.
The Minister of Energy and Resources recommends that the Committee:
  Note that Refining NZ plans to convert its Marsden Point oil refinery to a fuel import terminal and expects to make a final decision by 30 September 2021.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MBIE Report - Accelerating renewable - Refining NZ submission</title>
      <link>/reports/mbie-accelerating-renewables-rnz-submission/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/reports/mbie-accelerating-renewables-rnz-submission/</guid>
      <description>2020-03-02 Refining NZ Renewables </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MBIE Report - Accelerating renewable energy</title>
      <link>/reports/mbie-accelerating-renewables/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/reports/mbie-accelerating-renewables/</guid>
      <description>  MBIE - Accelerating renewable energy
  According to Megan Woods (ideological and unproven):
   The coming years will see a complete re-wiring of global energy systems in response to the threat of climate change, and the economic and environmental opportunities low emissions energy sources are creating
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MBIE Report - Accelerating renewable energy</title>
      <link>/reports/mbie-oil-security/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/reports/mbie-oil-security/</guid>
      <description>MBIE Oil security in New Zealand </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
