<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Timeline on Save Marsden Point</title>
    <link>/tags/timeline/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Timeline on Save Marsden Point</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 23 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/timeline/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Refinery $552M tax write off</title>
      <link>/history/2022-02-23-refiningnz-500m-tax-write-off/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/history/2022-02-23-refiningnz-500m-tax-write-off/</guid>
      <description>https://www.rnz.co.nz/news/business/462102/refining-new-zealand-posts-552m-loss https://www.nzx.com/announcements/386554
 2021-02-26 Visit to Marden Point  RNZ madee the decision to close the refinery in 2020 the most challenging in its 60 year history  Why wasn&amp;rsquo;t it supporrted like other businesses ? Thie year would have been the most profitable   RNZ also owns and operates the Refinery-Auckland Pipeline (RAP). Government only seemed interested in import terminal and Import only results in big reduction in stock - The Hale and Twomey reports outlines the dangers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cabinet From Hell Rejects Saving Refinery</title>
      <link>/history/2021-11-02-cabinet-closes-the-refinery/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/history/2021-11-02-cabinet-closes-the-refinery/</guid>
      <description>After a period of consultation Megan Woods signed the deth notice of the refinery with the release of the cabinet paper MBIE Cabinet Paper - Fuel supply resilience without a domestic oil refinery.
 Subject to a final decision by Refining NZ, due by 30 September 2021, oil refining operations are expected to cease between March and June 2022, after which 100 per cent of refined fuels will be imported. I propose to progress development of options to ensure domestic fuel stock levels remain adequate, as a means of supporting fuel supply resilience, as New Zealand transitions away from fossil fuels.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ardern Government Declares War on Carbon</title>
      <link>/history/2019-12-19-government-declares-war-on-carbon/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/history/2019-12-19-government-declares-war-on-carbon/</guid>
      <description>2018-11-12 Domestic oil and gas exploration ban  https://www.rnz.co.nz/news/political/375417/parliament-passes-bill-banning-new-offshore-oil-and-gas-exploration
https://www.google.com/search?q=CAB-18-MIN-0306.01&amp;amp;oq=CAB-18-MIN-0306.01&amp;amp;aqs=chrome..69i57.582j0j1&amp;amp;sourceid=chrome&amp;amp;ie=UTF-8 https://www.treasury.govt.nz/sites/default/files/2019-01/oia-20180503.pdf https://www.mbie.govt.nz/dmsdocument/6604-crown-minerals-act-1991-review-tranche-two-terms-of-reference-minute-of-decision-proactiverelease-pdf
Because of our distaince it&amp;rsquo;s better to get oiland gas locally.
The release of the MBIE document advising against a future for refining (as they had done for oil and gas exploration and production) came just before the Covid demand shock and after a long period of profit extraction by the shareholders and low refining margins because of excess capacity oversaes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fuel Cartel Sucks Profit Out of the Refinery</title>
      <link>/history/2012-11-01-rnz-processing-fee-purvin-gertz/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/history/2012-11-01-rnz-processing-fee-purvin-gertz/</guid>
      <description>2014-05-17 Refining NZ AGM - Fee Structure 2014-05-10 Refining shareholder faces unequal battle
   The company’s poor governance structure has contributed to its current problems.
    The board is dominated by oil company executives who are constantly changing. For example Refining NZ has had 44 different directors over the past decade.
    In addition the refinery’s chief executive or general manager has often been seconded from one of the major oil companies.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
