<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Topics on Save Marsden Point</title>
    <link>/topics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Topics on Save Marsden Point</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/topics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>About Us</title>
      <link>/topics/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/topics/about/</guid>
      <description>We are a team of patriot volunteers determinded to save New Zealand from the ravages of the communistc Ardern government. Like minded individuals and organizations are:
 Dig-In At Marsden Point Save Our Tankers Rebel Shareholder Bryan Halliweill Activist Investor Coralie van Camp The Late Great Brian Gaynor The Taxpayers Union The BFD  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bitumen</title>
      <link>/topics/bitumen/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/topics/bitumen/</guid>
      <description>  Imported bitumen
  NZTA takes control
  New Zealand | Imports and Exports
  Marsden Point to halt bitumen production
  New Zealand prepares for shifts in bitumen supply
  NZTA taking control of NZ&amp;rsquo;s supply of bitumen for roading
  Z leads bitumen market
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How We Think About Climate Change</title>
      <link>/topics/climate/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/topics/climate/</guid>
      <description>Sorry for the appeal to authority but herre are some CLimate Scientists whose measured attitude really resonate with us.
  William Happer
  Richard Lindzen
  Freeman Dyson
  Refining NZ Renewables
  https://www.stuff.co.nz/national/politics/opinion/128650738/emissions-plan-could-herald-the-biggest-set-of-changes-in-nz-since-rogernomics
It doesn&amp;rsquo;t immprove our livelihoods as our energy costs increase.
Climate Change =&amp;gt; Equitable, Prosperous, Innovative</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In The Press</title>
      <link>/topics/press/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/topics/press/</guid>
      <description>Jun 2021 - Marsden Point closure could expose NZ to fuel security risks    The Energy Minister said these risks are not significant, but a consultant&amp;rsquo;s report to the government says the opposite.
    Aug 2021 - Marsden Point refinery closure threatens energy security, Maritime Union says    Security and resilience were now the two most important factors for the economy. The closure of the refinery was corporate self-interest and not in the wider interests of New Zealand.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Miscellaneous Links</title>
      <link>/topics/daves-links/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/topics/daves-links/</guid>
      <description>Geopolitics  NZDF confirms Chinese spy ship entered NZ ‘economic zone’ NZ Navy vessles sold to Ireland China Solomons China Solomons OZ Pact Shipping Lanes SW Pacific Map  Fuel Security  Fuel firms set to be required to store more petrol in NZ after refinery closes Monitoing and enforcement of IEA emergency regime New Zealand confirms oil reserve release Could NZ run out of fuel if Marsden Pt oil refinery is closed  NZR Management and Shareholding  Andrew Brewer Andrew Brewer Experience Naomi James Earning Dec 2021 Refining NZ new CFO Refining NZ hires Santos exec Naomi James to take over as CEO ACC NZR directors shares in NZR NZR directors  Ampol Z acquistion  Ampol - Z Energy Aquisition Clearance Application Z Investors Directors Report Z Ampol sells Gull NZ Recent Insider Transactions - Z Energy  Geopolitics  Can NZR Survive End Looms for Kiwi Bitumen Oz govenrmnet help Oz buyout funds shareholders NZ &amp;lsquo;naive&amp;rsquo; to shut down Marsden Point - Australian analyst RNZ OIA Z energy-exiting-creude-oil-supply Fuel giant Z Energy agrees takeover deal with Australia&amp;rsquo;s Ampol NZ &amp;lsquo;naive&amp;rsquo; to shut down Marsden Point - Australian analyst  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ways To Secure Our Refinery</title>
      <link>/topics/govt-solution/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/topics/govt-solution/</guid>
      <description>One way to save the refinery would be to tariff imported refined products.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Oil Security in NZ</title>
      <link>/topics/suppy-chain-risks/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/topics/suppy-chain-risks/</guid>
      <description>MBIE Oil security in New Zealand https://www.interest.co.nz/public-policy/115592/government-planning-nzs-first-ever%C2%A0comprehensive-freight-and-supply-chain
 we put refinery capacity in the failure chain so we can have failures in   Foreign crude production Shipping (Crude) Refining Shipping (Distillate)   NZTA takes control New Zealand | Imports and Exports Marsden Point to halt bitumen production New Zealand prepares for shifts in bitumen supply  Addressing New Zealand&amp;rsquo;s oil Security in 2040  How might changes in the geopolitical environment affect the efficacy of New Zealand’s current oil security assessments and policies out to 2040?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
