<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Topics on Save Marsden Point</title>
    <link>/topics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Topics on Save Marsden Point</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/topics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>About Us</title>
      <link>/topics/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/topics/about/</guid>
      <description>We are patriot volunteers concerned enough about the perilous path our country has taken to try raise awareness to save her from the ravages of the communistc Ardern government.
Like minded individuals and organizations are:
 Dig-In At Marsden Point Save Our Tankers Rebel Shareholder Bryan Halliweill Activist Investor Coralie van Camp The Late Great Brian Gaynor The Taxpayers Union The BFD   Kia Kaha   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>All tags</title>
      <link>/topics/tags/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/topics/tags/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ownership</title>
      <link>/topics/how-to-save/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/topics/how-to-save/</guid>
      <description>Options of saving the refinery touch on a debate about the role of government in society and the economy. A government role may be useful in ensuring certain basic public services are provided in all circumstances.
Loan Tariff Organized Share Aquisition on Open Market Organized Share Aquisition on Open Market Nationalisation It concerns us that we are very late in shutting down a precious physical asset which we paid for simply to increase the profit sof a foreign company at a time where the economic zeitgiest is for reshoring industry.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ownership</title>
      <link>/topics/sovereignty-reshoring/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/topics/sovereignty-reshoring/</guid>
      <description>Losing the refinery is another step on the path to a loss of national economic sovreignty. As the world engages in re-shoring of supply chains and a rollback of naive globablism we should retain some form of ownership of the refinery to give us economic optionality and value. In particular the transfer of national assets to unrestricted private ownership where very often is foreign with no allegiance to the New Zealand people.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Refinery Operation</title>
      <link>/topics/operation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/topics/operation/</guid>
      <description>The refinery is a major contributor to New Zealands economy in many ways and its economic benefits are not easily or qucikly substitued.
Value of keeping the refinery:
 Cost is basically volatility. Ther Fuel Cartle ownership model - they were not incentivieed to run the refinery at a profit. For global multinationals the push is to globalise but they should never have had contorl of the reinfery The multinational don&amp;rsquo;t care about New Zealand The orginal sin was handing control over - it was very naive and relied on the  Costs   Environment</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fuel Security in NZ</title>
      <link>/topics/fuel-security/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/topics/fuel-security/</guid>
      <description>Despite government claims to the contrary, closure of Marsden Point has clearly decreased New Zealand&amp;rsquo;s fuel security because we have simply removed an option for supply, Where we previously may have imported direclty, imported crude or with modification process our own crude, now we are restricted to import only. The downside risks of no fuel scenarios would seems to have significantly increased. The government has probably overly foucsed on the benign recent geopolitical environemnt and given too much emphasis to the climate change policies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Climate</title>
      <link>/topics/climate/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/topics/climate/</guid>
      <description>We disagree with the premise of the great urgency of a move away from fossil fuels although an increasing depedence on alternatives is probably inevitable and desirable. One reason the NZ government let the refinery close was to meet climate emissions targets expressed through the ETS. The likelihood of the harmful man-made CO2 driven gobal warming apppears low and the mitigation technique appear to be ineffectual on climate and costly to our civilisation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Was The Refinery Closed ?</title>
      <link>/topics/daves-letter/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/topics/daves-letter/</guid>
      <description>Letter By Dave
Introduction This document intends to outline the New Zealand Labour governments’ complicity in the decommissioning of the refinery owned and operated by Refining NZ (RNZ) located at Marsden Point from being a crude oil refinery into a finished fuel product import only terminal. Additionally it will highlight various events, actions or responses that have occurred over the timeline of early 2020 up until events of the last few days.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
