<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Home on Save Marsden Point</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Home on Save Marsden Point</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 12 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Refinery closure to underpin emissions budget</title>
      <link>/events/2022-05-12-marsden-point-james-shaw-ets/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/events/2022-05-12-marsden-point-james-shaw-ets/</guid>
      <description>https://www.rnz.co.nz/news/political/466970/nz-s-first-three-emissions-budgets-guaranteed-with-non-partisan-support-minister
 But most of this is expected to be met by the Marsden Point oil refinery closure, which will reduce the country’s emissions by about 2.5 Mt in the first emissions budget period to 2025. That means the country will only have to reduce its projected emissions from other sources by an average of 0.6 Mt during this period.
 The First Union said last month that, if the Marsden Point refinery did close, the net result would be a net rise in global carbon emissions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Naomi James Closes Marsden Point Refinery</title>
      <link>/events/2022-04-16-audio-naomi-james-closes-marsden-point/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/events/2022-04-16-audio-naomi-james-closes-marsden-point/</guid>
      <description>Naomi James Closes Marsden Point
   Simon Terry - Systainability Council CEO asks How much would it cost to reconfigure to process liocal crude to which James (a lawyer) replies Yeah, I don&#39;t have an eact number for that - not good enough for 2M per year.
   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Megan Woods Defends Closing Marsden Point</title>
      <link>/events/2022-03-11-audio-woods-on-fuel-security/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/events/2022-03-11-audio-woods-on-fuel-security/</guid>
      <description>Energy Minister Megan Woods on NZ&amp;rsquo;s fuel security</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Closing Marsden Point amid global oil uncertainty</title>
      <link>/events/2022-03-07-audio-closing-marsden-point-geopolitics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/events/2022-03-07-audio-closing-marsden-point-geopolitics/</guid>
      <description>The sticky issue of closing Marsden Point amid global oil uncertainty</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Woods visits Marsden Point</title>
      <link>/events/2022-02-26-woods-visitis-marsden-point/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/events/2022-02-26-woods-visitis-marsden-point/</guid>
      <description>2021-02-26 Visit to Marden Point  RNZ madee the decision to close the refinery in 2020 the most challenging in its 60 year history  Why wasn&amp;rsquo;t it supporrted like other businesses ? Thie year would have been the most profitable   RNZ also owns and operates the Refinery-Auckland Pipeline (RAP). Government only seemed interested in import terminal and Import only results in big reduction in stock - The Hale and Twomey reports outlines the dangers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Refinery $552M tax write off</title>
      <link>/events/2022-02-23-refiningnz-500m-tax-write-off/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/events/2022-02-23-refiningnz-500m-tax-write-off/</guid>
      <description>https://www.rnz.co.nz/news/business/462102/refining-new-zealand-posts-552m-loss
https://www.nzx.com/announcements/386554</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Us</title>
      <link>/topics/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/topics/about/</guid>
      <description>We are a team of patriot volunteers determinded to save New Zealand from the ravages of the communistc Ardern government. Like minded individuals and organizations are:
 Dig-In At Marsden Point Save Our Tankers Rebel Shareholder Bryan Halliweill Activist Investor Coralie van Camp The Late Great Brian Gaynor The Taxpayers Union The BFD  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bitumen</title>
      <link>/topics/bitumen/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/topics/bitumen/</guid>
      <description>  Imported bitumen
  NZTA takes control
  New Zealand | Imports and Exports
  Marsden Point to halt bitumen production
  New Zealand prepares for shifts in bitumen supply
  NZTA taking control of NZ&amp;rsquo;s supply of bitumen for roading
  Z leads bitumen market
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How We Think About Climate Change</title>
      <link>/topics/climate/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/topics/climate/</guid>
      <description>Sorry for the appeal to authority but herre are some CLimate Scientists whose measured attitude really resonate with us.
  William Happer
  Richard Lindzen
  Freeman Dyson
  Refining NZ Renewables
  https://www.stuff.co.nz/national/politics/opinion/128650738/emissions-plan-could-herald-the-biggest-set-of-changes-in-nz-since-rogernomics
It doesn&amp;rsquo;t immprove our livelihoods as our energy costs increase.
Climate Change =&amp;gt; Equitable, Prosperous, Innovative</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In The Press</title>
      <link>/topics/press/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/topics/press/</guid>
      <description>Jun 2021 - Marsden Point closure could expose NZ to fuel security risks    The Energy Minister said these risks are not significant, but a consultant&amp;rsquo;s report to the government says the opposite.
    Aug 2021 - Marsden Point refinery closure threatens energy security, Maritime Union says    Security and resilience were now the two most important factors for the economy. The closure of the refinery was corporate self-interest and not in the wider interests of New Zealand.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Miscellaneous Links</title>
      <link>/topics/daves-links/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/topics/daves-links/</guid>
      <description>Geopolitics  NZDF confirms Chinese spy ship entered NZ ‘economic zone’ NZ Navy vessles sold to Ireland China Solomons China Solomons OZ Pact Shipping Lanes SW Pacific Map  Fuel Security  Fuel firms set to be required to store more petrol in NZ after refinery closes Monitoing and enforcement of IEA emergency regime New Zealand confirms oil reserve release Could NZ run out of fuel if Marsden Pt oil refinery is closed  NZR Management and Shareholding  Andrew Brewer Andrew Brewer Experience Naomi James Earning Dec 2021 Refining NZ new CFO Refining NZ hires Santos exec Naomi James to take over as CEO ACC NZR directors shares in NZR NZR directors  Ampol Z acquistion  Ampol - Z Energy Aquisition Clearance Application Z Investors Directors Report Z Ampol sells Gull NZ Recent Insider Transactions - Z Energy  Geopolitics  Can NZR Survive End Looms for Kiwi Bitumen Oz govenrmnet help Oz buyout funds shareholders NZ &amp;lsquo;naive&amp;rsquo; to shut down Marsden Point - Australian analyst RNZ OIA Z energy-exiting-creude-oil-supply Fuel giant Z Energy agrees takeover deal with Australia&amp;rsquo;s Ampol NZ &amp;lsquo;naive&amp;rsquo; to shut down Marsden Point - Australian analyst  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ways To Secure Our Refinery</title>
      <link>/topics/govt-solution/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/topics/govt-solution/</guid>
      <description>One way to save the refinery would be to tariff imported refined products.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MBIE Cabinet Paper</title>
      <link>/events/2021-12-15-mbie-cabpaper-minimum-onshore-stockholding/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/events/2021-12-15-mbie-cabpaper-minimum-onshore-stockholding/</guid>
      <description>Minimum Onshore Fuel Stockholding </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cabinet Rejects Saving Refinery</title>
      <link>/events/2021-11-02-mbie-cabpaper-woods-closes-the-refinery/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/events/2021-11-02-mbie-cabpaper-woods-closes-the-refinery/</guid>
      <description>MBIE Cabinet Paper - Fuel supply resilience without a domestic oil refinery I propose to progress development of options to ensure domestic fuel stock levels remain adequate, as a means of supporting fuel supply resilience, as New Zealand transitions away from fossil fuels.
implications for meeting the Government’s first emissions reduction budget.
The Minister of Energy and Resources recommends that the Committee:
  Note that Refining NZ plans to convert its Marsden Point oil refinery to a fuel import terminal and expects to make a final decision by 30 September 2021.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hale and Twomey - Fuel stockholding costs and benefits</title>
      <link>/events/2020-12-16-mbie-hale-twomey-fuel-security-costs-benefits/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/events/2020-12-16-mbie-hale-twomey-fuel-security-costs-benefits/</guid>
      <description>As MBIE pushed ahead with apthe decision not to act to preven the Marsden Point Refinery closure, they commissioined this report.
2020-12-16 Fuel security and fuel stockholding costs and benefits </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RNZ announces strategic review</title>
      <link>/events/2020-04-15-rnz-strategic-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/events/2020-04-15-rnz-strategic-review/</guid>
      <description>  2020-04-15 RNZ Announces Strategic Review at start of Covid
 low refining margins globally and oversupply in the Asia region. capital structure to maximise value for shareholders.    2020-04-30 RNZ strategic Review
 strategic review options  Continue current refinery model Alter refinery operating model Separate refining and infrastructure assets Convert to an import terminal      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hale and Twomey - Impact of Import Only</title>
      <link>/events/2020-03-23-mbie-hale-twomey-impact-import-only/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/events/2020-03-23-mbie-hale-twomey-impact-import-only/</guid>
      <description>Highly skilled jobs and manufacturing capability - RNZ currently employs around 400 people directly, a similar number indirectly - Less demand for the current New Zealand coastal shipping fleet - RNZ contributes about $10 million to the largely fixed cost of supplying electricity, water and other utilities - RNZ employs about 120 skilled engineers with specialist expertise in energy whose skills may not have alternate sources of employment in New Zealand.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Oil Security in NZ</title>
      <link>/topics/suppy-chain-risks/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/topics/suppy-chain-risks/</guid>
      <description>MBIE Oil security in New Zealand https://www.interest.co.nz/public-policy/115592/government-planning-nzs-first-ever%C2%A0comprehensive-freight-and-supply-chain
 we put refinery capacity in the failure chain so we can have failures in   Foreign crude production Shipping (Crude) Refining Shipping (Distillate)   NZTA takes control New Zealand | Imports and Exports Marsden Point to halt bitumen production New Zealand prepares for shifts in bitumen supply  Addressing New Zealand&amp;rsquo;s oil Security in 2040  How might changes in the geopolitical environment affect the efficacy of New Zealand’s current oil security assessments and policies out to 2040?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MBIE Disscussion Document - Accelerating renewable energy</title>
      <link>/events/2019-12-19-mbie-accelarating-renewable-refiningnz-dialogue/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/events/2019-12-19-mbie-accelarating-renewable-refiningnz-dialogue/</guid>
      <description>The release of the MBIE document advising against a future for refining (as they had done for oil and gas exploration and production) came just before the Covid demand shock and after a long period of profit extraction by the shareholders and low refining margins because of excess capacity oversaes.
  2020-04-20 RNZ to engage with MBIE with regard to
 security of fuel supply for New Zealand importance of refining capability and optionality for fuel supply the contribution of RNZ to the Northland economy the role of RNZ’s skills and assets in a transition to lower carbon fuels    MBIE - Accelerating renewable energy</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Oil and Gas Exploration Ban</title>
      <link>/events/2018-11-12-oil-gas-ban/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/events/2018-11-12-oil-gas-ban/</guid>
      <description>2018-11-12 Domestic oil and gas exploration ban  https://www.rnz.co.nz/news/political/375417/parliament-passes-bill-banning-new-offshore-oil-and-gas-exploration
https://www.google.com/search?q=CAB-18-MIN-0306.01&amp;amp;oq=CAB-18-MIN-0306.01&amp;amp;aqs=chrome..69i57.582j0j1&amp;amp;sourceid=chrome&amp;amp;ie=UTF-8 https://www.treasury.govt.nz/sites/default/files/2019-01/oia-20180503.pdf https://www.mbie.govt.nz/dmsdocument/6604-crown-minerals-act-1991-review-tranche-two-terms-of-reference-minute-of-decision-proactiverelease-pdf
Because of our distaince it&amp;rsquo;s better to get oiland gas locally.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Report into Refining NZ Processing Fee</title>
      <link>/events/2012-rnz-processing-fee-purvin-gertz/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/events/2012-rnz-processing-fee-purvin-gertz/</guid>
      <description>2012 Purvin and Gertz Report</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fuel Cartel Takes 30% Discount from our Refinery</title>
      <link>/events/1995-01-01-cartel-gives-themselves-30pct-dicount/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 1995 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/events/1995-01-01-cartel-gives-themselves-30pct-dicount/</guid>
      <description>2014-05-17 Refining NZ AGM - Fee Structure 2014-05-10 Refining shareholder faces unequal battle
   The company’s poor governance structure has contributed to its current problems.
    The board is dominated by oil company executives who are constantly changing. For example Refining NZ has had 44 different directors over the past decade.
    In addition the refinery’s chief executive or general manager has often been seconded from one of the major oil companies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Public gifts Refining NZ \$2 billion hydrocracker</title>
      <link>/events/1988-01-01-rnz-gifted-2b-hydrocracker/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 1988 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/events/1988-01-01-rnz-gifted-2b-hydrocracker/</guid>
      <description>Brian Gaynor reports in 2014 that:
 Refining NZ listed on the NZX in September 1962, received its first tanker of Kuwait feedstock in February 1964 and was officially opened by Prime Minister Keith Holyoake three months later. Refinery margins were government controlled. The original refinery was built as a simple hydroskimming refinery, which is a crude distiller unit with limited secondary upgrading. Prime Minister Robert Muldoon included the expansion of the Marsden Point refinery as one of his “Think Big” projects in the early 1980s.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scratch</title>
      <link>/scratch/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/scratch/</guid>
      <description>The government could yet intervene as has for other critical public goods such as Kiwirail, Air New Zealand and Tiwai Point and Ihumatao Government intervention was discuseed in a Megan Woods cabinet paper, but willfully ignored. We could encourage different ownership structures nwith the type of planning horizon necessary for such a crucial asset.  https://carbon-pulse.com/category/new-zealand/
https://www.newsroom.co.nz/one-cent-a-litre-to-insure-against-no-fuel-for-essential-services https://www.nzx.com/announcements/375073
http://nzx-prod-s7fsd7f98s.s3-website-ap-southeast-2.amazonaws.com/attachments/NZR/375073/349617.pdf
https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=pwvVephTIHU
https://www.rnz.co.nz/news/business/448612/marsden-point-potential-closure-government-defends-import-only-strategy
https://www.mbie.govt.nz/building-and-energy/energy-and-natural-resources/energy-generation-and-markets/liquid-fuel-market/
https://www.mbie.govt.nz/building-and-energy/energy-and-natural-resources/energy-generation-and-markets/liquid-fuel-market/oil-security-in-new-zealand/
Refinery</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
