<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Home on Save Marsden Point</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Home on Save Marsden Point</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 26 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Woods visits Marsden Point</title>
      <link>/event/2022-02-26-woods-visitis-marsden-point/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/event/2022-02-26-woods-visitis-marsden-point/</guid>
      <description>2021-02-26 Visit to Marden Point  RNZ madee the decision to close the refinery in 2020 the most challenging in its 60 year history  Why wasn&amp;rsquo;t it supporrted like other businesses ? Thie year would have been the most profitable   RNZ also owns and operates the Refinery-Auckland Pipeline (RAP). Government only seemed interested in import terminal and Import only results in big reduction in stock - The Hale and Twomey reports outlines the dangers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Implications of replacing refinery with import terminal</title>
      <link>/event/2020-06-03-mbie-implications-of-import-only/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/event/2020-06-03-mbie-implications-of-import-only/</guid>
      <description>2020-06-03 MBIE - Implications of replacing refinery with import terminal  Highly skilled jobs and manufacturing capability  RNZ currently employs around 400 people directly, a similar number indirectly Less demand for the current New Zealand coastal shipping fleet RNZ contributes about $10 million to the largely fixed cost of supplying electricity, water and other utilities RNZ employs about 120 skilled engineers with specialist expertise in energy whose skills may not have alternate sources of employment in New Zealand.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RNZ asks for help</title>
      <link>/event/2020-07-01-rnz-asks-for-help/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/event/2020-07-01-rnz-asks-for-help/</guid>
      <description>2020-06-03 Response to RNZ’s strategic review questions  very interesting   2020-06-25 Refining NZ provides update on Strategic Review  Simplify operations   2020-06-05 RNZ seeks government input on  Strategic importance of maintaining refining capacity in New Zealand. Impact of change to import model on NZ&amp;rsquo;s IEA oil stock obligation. Changes in government policy for fuel supply chain resilience. Options for RNZ to access cheaper electricity and gas.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RNZ releases strategic review</title>
      <link>/event/2020-04-30-rnz-strategic-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/event/2020-04-30-rnz-strategic-review/</guid>
      <description> 2020-04-30 RNZ strategic Review  strategic review options  Continue current refinery model Alter refinery operating model Separate refining and infrastructure assets Convert to an import terminal      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RNZ Announces Strategic Review at start of Covid</title>
      <link>/event/2020-04-15-rnz-strategic-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/event/2020-04-15-rnz-strategic-review/</guid>
      <description> 2020-04-15 RNZ Announces Strategic Review at start of Covid  low refining margins globally and oversupply in the Asia region. capital structure to maximise value for shareholders.    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RNZ to engage with MBIE</title>
      <link>/event/2020-04-20-rnz-to-engage-mbie/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/event/2020-04-20-rnz-to-engage-mbie/</guid>
      <description>ipsum loren
 2020-04-20 RNZ to engage with MBIE with regard to  security of fuel supply for New Zealand importance of refining capability and optionality for fuel supply the contribution of RNZ to the Northland economy the role of RNZ’s skills and assets in a transition to lower carbon fuels    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Oil and Gas Exploration Ban</title>
      <link>/event/2020-04-15-mbie-report-conversion-to-fules-only/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/event/2020-04-15-mbie-report-conversion-to-fules-only/</guid>
      <description>2020-04-15 Indpendent Report for MBIE - Impact of Conversion to Fuels Terminal  The change of the Marsden Point facility to a fuels terminal would have a significant impact of New Zealand&amp;rsquo;s fuel security including:  A reduction in physical inventories (expected to be 25-30%) that ultimately is likely to impact New Zealand&amp;rsquo;s supply security; An increased cost of compliance to meet the IEA membership requirement to hold stocks covering at least 90 days of New Zealand&amp;rsquo;s daily net import requirement; The loss of the coastal tanker operation and the expertise associated with that (albeit import tankers would increase so there would still be plenty of ships on the coast); No ability in New Zealand to correct product that is significantly off-specification which needs to be taken into account with stock level decisions; Possible issues with jet import availability if it all needs to meet a lower sulphur specification for transport via RAP; No local supply of sulphur for fertiliser; replacement supply needed for CO2; Loss of technical processing expertise; and Loss of ability to process New Zealand crude in a major supply emergency (global meltdown or pandemic where New Zealand might be isolated for a time).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NZ seeks guidance from MBIE on just transition to low carbon future</title>
      <link>/event/2020-03-06-rnz-seeks-guidance/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/event/2020-03-06-rnz-seeks-guidance/</guid>
      <description> 2020-03-06 RNZ seeks guidance from MBIE on just transition to low carbon future  RNZ reminds the government  RNZ refines imported crude intp 70% of NZ&amp;rsquo;s transport fuel need. Import of refined products equates to an export of GDP. The refinery is a platform for the production of low emission fuels.      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MBIE discussion paper - Accelerating renewable energy</title>
      <link>/event/2019-12-19-mbie-accelerating-renewables/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/event/2019-12-19-mbie-accelerating-renewables/</guid>
      <description>ipsum loren
 2019-12-19 MBIE discussion paper - Accelerating renewable energy  According to Megan Woods (ideological and unproven):  The coming years will see a complete re-wiring of global energy systems in response to the threat of climate change, and the economic and environmental opportunities low emissions energy sources are creating
     </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Oil and Gas Exploration Ban</title>
      <link>/event/2018-11-12-oil-gas-ban/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/event/2018-11-12-oil-gas-ban/</guid>
      <description>ipsum loren
 2018-11-12 Domestic oil and gas exploration ban  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>All topics</title>
      <link>/page/all-topics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/page/all-topics/</guid>
      <description>All topics are.
 Megan Woods Namoi Woods Kerosene Bitumen Catalyst Climate Change  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bitumen</title>
      <link>/page/risks-of-failure/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/page/risks-of-failure/</guid>
      <description> Imported bitumen NZTA takes control New Zealand | Imports and Exports Marsden Point to halt bitumen production New Zealand prepares for shifts in bitumen supply  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bitumen</title>
      <link>/page/tobias-dalley-thesis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/page/tobias-dalley-thesis/</guid>
      <description> Imported bitumen NZTA takes control New Zealand | Imports and Exports Marsden Point to halt bitumen production New Zealand prepares for shifts in bitumen supply  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dave&#39;s Links</title>
      <link>/page/dave-nzr/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/page/dave-nzr/</guid>
      <description> Andrew Brewer Experience Andrew Brewer Refining NZ hires Santos exec Naomi James to take over as CEO Can NZR Survive End Looms for Kiwi Bitumen Oz govenrmnet help Oz buyout funds shareholders NZ &amp;lsquo;naive&amp;rsquo; to shut down Marsden Point - Australian analyst RNZ OIA Z energy-exiting-creude-oil-supply Fuel giant Z Energy agrees takeover deal with Australia&amp;rsquo;s Ampol RNZ confirms fuel only NZDF confirms Chinese spy ship entered NZ ‘economic zone’ Fuel firms required to store more pterol Refining NZ new CFO War changes NZ fuel needs NZ NAvy vessles sold to Ireland Ampol sells Gull NZ Z leads bitumen market NZ to release oil reserves NZTA taking control of bitumen China Solomons China Solomons OZ Pact Monitoing and enforcement of emergency regime Shipping Lanes SW Pacific Map Naomi James Earning Dec 2021 ACC NZR directors shares in NZR Recent Insider Transactions - Z Energy Ampol - Z Energy Aquisition Clearance Application Z Investors NZR directors Directors Report Z Oz Analyst - NZR Naive - audio NZ Could run out of fuel if Marsden closed - audio  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Energy Market</title>
      <link>/page/energy-market/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/page/energy-market/</guid>
      <description> MBIE - Oil Statistics Wiki Oil and Gas in NZ NZ Energy Sourcees The fuel industry in New Zealand A bizarre emissions declaration Refining NZ Renewables A bizarre emissions declaration Refining NZ Renewables  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hale and Twomey Report</title>
      <link>/page/report-import-only-impact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/page/report-import-only-impact/</guid>
      <description>The March 2020 Hale and Twomey report commisioned by MBIE - and subsequently ignored, made the following points about the impact of a move to an import only model:
 A reduction in physical inventories (expected to be 25-30%) that ultimately is likely to impact New Zealand&amp;rsquo;s supply security An increased cost of compliance to meet the IEA membership requirement to hold stocks covering at least 90 days of New Zealand&amp;rsquo;s daily net import requirement; The loss of the coastal tanker operation and the expertise associated with that (albeit import tankers would increase so there would still be plenty of ships on the coast) No ability in New Zealand to correct product that is significantly off-specification which needs to be taken into account with stock level decisions Possible issues with jet import availability if it all needs to meet a lower sulphur specification for transport via RAP; No local supply of sulphur for fertiliser; replacement supply needed for CO2; Loss of technical processing expertise; Loss of ability to process New Zealand crude in a major supply emergency (global meltdown or pandemic where New Zealand might be isolated for a time).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In The Press</title>
      <link>/page/in-the-press/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/page/in-the-press/</guid>
      <description>Refinery/
 Jun 2021 - Marsden Point closure could expose NZ to fuel security risks    The Energy Minister said these risks are not significant, but a consultant&amp;rsquo;s report to the government says the opposite.
    Aug 2021 - Marsden Point refinery closure threatens energy security, Maritime Union says    Security and resilience were now the two most important factors for the economy. The closure of the refinery was corporate self-interest and not in the wider interests of New Zealand.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In The Press</title>
      <link>/page/mbie-correspondence/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/page/mbie-correspondence/</guid>
      <description> 2020-01-01 Andrew Hume Correspondence 2022-01-01 James Sigilo Correspondence 2022-01-01 Shane Wilson Correspondence (Tiwai Point)  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Refining NZ Strategic Review</title>
      <link>/page/refinery-strategic-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/page/refinery-strategic-review/</guid>
      <description>  A bizarre emissions declaration
  Refining NZ Renewables
  A bizarre emissions declaration
  Refining NZ Renewables
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scratch</title>
      <link>/scratch/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/scratch/</guid>
      <description>The government could yet intervene as has for other critical public goods such as Kiwirail, Air New Zealand and Tiwai Point and Ihumatao Government intervention was discuseed in a Megan Woods cabinet paper, but willfully ignored. We could encourage different ownership structures nwith the type of planning horizon necessary for such a crucial asset.  https://carbon-pulse.com/category/new-zealand/
https://www.newsroom.co.nz/one-cent-a-litre-to-insure-against-no-fuel-for-essential-services https://www.nzx.com/announcements/375073
http://nzx-prod-s7fsd7f98s.s3-website-ap-southeast-2.amazonaws.com/attachments/NZR/375073/349617.pdf
https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=pwvVephTIHU
https://www.rnz.co.nz/news/business/448612/marsden-point-potential-closure-government-defends-import-only-strategy
https://www.mbie.govt.nz/building-and-energy/energy-and-natural-resources/energy-generation-and-markets/liquid-fuel-market/
https://www.mbie.govt.nz/building-and-energy/energy-and-natural-resources/energy-generation-and-markets/liquid-fuel-market/oil-security-in-new-zealand/
https://www.hydrocarbons-technology.com/projects/marsdenpointrefinery/</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Taking care of the environment</title>
      <link>/page/environment/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/page/environment/</guid>
      <description>Gerrman shuttering nuclear
  A bizarre emissions declaration
  Refining NZ Renewables
  A bizarre emissions declaration
  Refining NZ Renewables
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Taking care of the environment</title>
      <link>/page/govt-finances/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/page/govt-finances/</guid>
      <description>Gerrman shuttering nuclear
 A bizarre emissions declaration  </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
