<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Home on A minimal Hugo website</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Home on A minimal Hugo website</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 16 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Statistical FHIR</title>
      <link>/post/2022/01/16/statistical-fhir/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2022/01/16/statistical-fhir/</guid>
      <description>FHIR concerns itself principally with recording healthcare system events and less about modeling. Every event recorded by a FHIR system may be modeled to predict its future behavior, and the estimates of the modeled distribution parameters conveniently stored in the FHIR schema. It does not appear to be prescribed or suggested how to to this.
One idea is to abstract away the modeled quantity e.g. duration in an FHIR Task and replace this by the parameters of the distribution of task time (mean and standard deviation if Gaussian), and store these instead of the realized instance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/post/1/01/01/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/1/01/01/</guid>
      <description>Entities  forecastable(forecastable_id,&amp;hellip;) &amp;ndash; all the static information forecast_type(forecast_type,&amp;hellip;) forecast(forecastable_id,date,horizon,forecast_type,value) forecastable_history(forecastable_id,date,value) forecastable_consumer_history(forecastable_id,consumer_post_id,effects&amp;hellip;) # consumer_post(consumer_post_id,date,url) - file, leave in ES design_matrix - long form forecastable_history and forecastable_consumer_history gathered wide  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Hugo XMin</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>XMin is the first Hugo theme I have designed. The original reason that I wrote it was I needed a minimal example of Hugo themes when I was writing the blogdown book. Basically I wanted a simple theme that supports a navigation menu, a home page, other single pages, lists of pages, blog posts, categories, tags, and RSS. That is all. Nothing fancy. In terms of CSS and JavaScript, I really want to keep them minimal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Hugo XMin</title>
      <link>/company/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/company/</guid>
      <description>We are experienced implementors of FHIR, the future standard of healthcare technology inter-operability. We are experts in data extraction, migration, mining and machine learning for any problem domain. We have deep experience in the valuation and risk management of financial instruments. We can help you publish and monetize your data or idea by providing an API to other businesses or the developer community. We can help sell directly to consumers with a single page web-app or mobile application as the shop-front of your business.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
