<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Events on Save Marsden Point</title>
    <link>/event/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Events on Save Marsden Point</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 12 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/event/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Refinery Closure to Underpin Emissions Budget</title>
      <link>/event/2022-05-12-marsden-point-james-shaw-ets/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/event/2022-05-12-marsden-point-james-shaw-ets/</guid>
      <description>https://www.rnz.co.nz/news/political/466970/nz-s-first-three-emissions-budgets-guaranteed-with-non-partisan-support-minister
But most of this is expected to be met by the Marsden Point oil refinery closure, which will reduce the country’s emissions by about 2.5 Mt in the first emissions budget period to 2025. That means the country will only have to reduce its projected emissions from other sources by an average of 0.6 Mt during this period.
The First Union said last month that, if the Marsden Point refinery did close, the net result would be a net rise in global carbon emissions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Refinery $552M tax write off</title>
      <link>/event/2022-02-23-refiningnz-500m-tax-write-off/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/event/2022-02-23-refiningnz-500m-tax-write-off/</guid>
      <description>https://www.rnz.co.nz/news/business/462102/refining-new-zealand-posts-552m-loss https://www.nzx.com/announcements/386554
2021-02-26 Visit to Marden Point RNZ madee the decision to close the refinery in 2020 the most challenging in its 60 year history Why wasn&amp;rsquo;t it supporrted like other businesses ? Thie year would have been the most profitable RNZ also owns and operates the Refinery-Auckland Pipeline (RAP). Government only seemed interested in import terminal and Import only results in big reduction in stock - The Hale and Twomey reports outlines the dangers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cabinet From Hell Rejects Saving Refinery</title>
      <link>/event/2021-11-02-cabinet-closes-the-refinery/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/event/2021-11-02-cabinet-closes-the-refinery/</guid>
      <description>After a period of consultation Megan Woods signed the deth notice of the refinery with the release of the cabinet paper MBIE Cabinet Paper - Fuel supply resilience without a domestic oil refinery.
Subject to a final decision by Refining NZ, due by 30 September 2021, oil refining operations are expected to cease between March and June 2022, after which 100 per cent of refined fuels will be imported. I propose to progress development of options to ensure domestic fuel stock levels remain adequate, as a means of supporting fuel supply resilience, as New Zealand transitions away from fossil fuels.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Refining NZ Strategic Review</title>
      <link>/event/2020-04-15-rnz-strategic-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/event/2020-04-15-rnz-strategic-review/</guid>
      <description> get the old finanicial statements.
2020-04-15 RNZ Announces Strategic Review at start of Covid
low refining margins globally and oversupply in the Asia region. capital structure to maximise value for shareholders. 2020-04-30 RNZ strategic Review
strategic review options Continue current refinery model Alter refinery operating model Separate refining and infrastructure assets Convert to an import terminal </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ardern Government Declares War on Carbon</title>
      <link>/event/2019-12-19-government-declares-war-on-carbon/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/event/2019-12-19-government-declares-war-on-carbon/</guid>
      <description>2018-11-12 Domestic oil and gas exploration ban https://www.rnz.co.nz/news/political/375417/parliament-passes-bill-banning-new-offshore-oil-and-gas-exploration
https://www.google.com/search?q=CAB-18-MIN-0306.01&amp;amp;oq=CAB-18-MIN-0306.01&amp;amp;aqs=chrome..69i57.582j0j1&amp;amp;sourceid=chrome&amp;amp;ie=UTF-8 https://www.treasury.govt.nz/sites/default/files/2019-01/oia-20180503.pdf https://www.mbie.govt.nz/dmsdocument/6604-crown-minerals-act-1991-review-tranche-two-terms-of-reference-minute-of-decision-proactiverelease-pdf
Because of our distaince it&amp;rsquo;s better to get oiland gas locally.
The release of the MBIE document advising against a future for refining (as they had done for oil and gas exploration and production) came just before the Covid demand shock and after a long period of profit extraction by the shareholders and low refining margins because of excess capacity oversaes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fuel Cartel Sucks Profit Out of the Refinery</title>
      <link>/event/2012-11-01-rnz-processing-fee-purvin-gertz/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/event/2012-11-01-rnz-processing-fee-purvin-gertz/</guid>
      <description>2014-05-17 Refining NZ AGM - Fee Structure 2014-05-10 Refining shareholder faces unequal battle
The company’s poor governance structure has contributed to its current problems.
The board is dominated by oil company executives who are constantly changing. For example Refining NZ has had 44 different directors over the past decade.
In addition the refinery’s chief executive or general manager has often been seconded from one of the major oil companies.
These oil companies, which have a combined 72.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Public Gifts Fuel Cartel a \$2B Hydrocracker</title>
      <link>/event/1988-01-01-rnz-gifted-2b-hydrocracker/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 1988 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/event/1988-01-01-rnz-gifted-2b-hydrocracker/</guid>
      <description>Brian Gaynor reports in 2014 that:
Refining NZ listed on the NZX in September 1962, received its first tanker of Kuwait feedstock in February 1964 and was officially opened by Prime Minister Keith Holyoake three months later. Refinery margins were government controlled. The original refinery was built as a simple hydroskimming refinery, which is a crude distiller unit with limited secondary upgrading. Prime Minister Robert Muldoon included the expansion of the Marsden Point refinery as one of his “Think Big” projects in the early 1980s.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
